Simon Villeneuve

Content Strategist

Summary

Simon is an experienced marketing communications leader with a consistent track record of building high-performing teams from scratch, improving profitability, and implementing successful department-wide processes. He is a dedicated leader focused on helping innovative brands tell better stories that inspire their customers to buy. His collaborative style works extremely well with customers and colleagues alike.

Professional Experience

Content Director / Pneuma33 Creative / Jan. 2016–Present

Responsible for the oversight of all content projects for Pneuma33 Creative and their clients. He currently leads a team of two in-house content experts as well as 25 independent freelancers to complete a variety of content projects on-time and on-budget.

Digital Community Specialist / Faithlife Corporation / June 2014–Jan. 2016
Pioneered an innovative content strategy that organically drove 3,000+ unique pageviews per month for LogosCloud.com. The blog was consistently a top converting channel in less than 90 days.

SimonVilleneuve.co / 541.570.0620 / SimonVilleneuveCo@gmail.com
As always, references are available upon request.

Professional Experience Continued

Marketing Coordinator / Tooth & Nail Records / June 2013–June 2014
Managed and coordinated music liscensing for 52 artists (over 600 songs).
During a contract with Omnicom, as well as others, he helped commercial placements on TNT, CW's the 100, and more.

Marketing Communications Assistant / Agros International / July 2013–Apr. 2014 Functioned as the primary in-house marketing associate. Designed web and print content, wrote compelling copy for outbound marketing efforts and social media profiles.

Education

Seattle Pacific University / Seattle, WA
Music Composition & Business Administration
Attended 2011-2014

Certifications

Inbound Certification / Hubspot / Dec. 2015–Jan. 2017

SimonVilleneuve.co / 541.570.0620 / SimonVilleneuveCo@gmail.com